http://belmontabbey.org.uk/privacypolicy

About Belmont Abbey's Privacy Policy
Belmont Abbey is a charity registered with the Charity Commission in England and Wales. Our charity number is 226278 and our registered address is Ruckhall Lane, Hereford, HR2 9RZ. In this Notice, references to ‘we’ and ‘us’ means the
Belmont Abbey General Trust.When you provide us with Personal Data in order to engage with us and/or benefit from our activities, we will keep a record of the data you give to us in order to enable us to comply with our statutory obligations and to achieve our charitable objects of advancing and maintaining the Roman Catholic religion through the operation of our Monastery and our other activities.For the purpose of the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/279 (GDPR), Belmont Abbey through its Trustees will be a Data Controller in respect of your Personal Data. In some cases, Belmont Abbey may be a joint Data Controller of your Personal Data (e.g. where your data is shared between the us and another organisation for a particular purpose). Please be aware that the parishes at which members of our community serve will belong to the Belmont Abbey Mission Trust or the relevant local Diocese (Different Registered Charities ). These are separate legal entities and will have their own applicable Data Controllers who process Personal Data on their behalf. Details of these can be found within the individual parish websites served.Everyone has rights with regard to how their Personal Data is handled by organisations. Belmont Abbey is committed to ensuring that Personal Data is properly and securely managed in accordance with the relevant data protection laws, and believes this is an important part of achieving trust and confidence between the Abbey and those with whom it interacts. Please read this Notice to understand how we use and protect the information that you provide to us or that we obtain or hold about you, and to understand what your rights are in relation to information that we hold. This Notice applies to information about living identifiable individuals only.
How and why do we Process your Personal Data?
The Personal Data which we hold about you, whether it is collected directly from 		you or whether we receive it from a third party, may be Processed in a number of 	ways, for example:•	to communicate with you in relation to news about or activities and events 			taking place at Belmont Abbey or in an associated parish, 			including seeking feedback and informing you of any changes to 				our activities;•	to improve our activities and the way we communicate with you,
including our 		website;•	to carry out our activities, from weddings and funerals to retreats and general pastoral 			and spiritual care;•	to process donations that you may make to us or other payments where, for 		example, you may utilise the services of Hedley Lodge or purchase goods from within our shop.•	to administer, support, improve and develop the administration of the 			Belmont Abbey’s work and operations and to keep our accounts and records 		up-to-date;•	to process applications from you, including registration information for retreats at Belmont Abbey;•	to ensure we comply with our legal obligations (e.g. by providing information 		to the Charity Commission or HMRC or carrying out safeguarding activities) 		and•	in the case of CCTV recordings, to prevent or detect crime, and to help 			create a safer environment for our staff, parishioners and visitors.Any information gathered through cookies and similar technologies via the website, is used to measure and analyse information on visits to the website, to tailor the website to make it better for visitors and to improve technical performance. We will not use the data to identify you personally or to make any decisions about you.
On what Grounds do we Process your Personal Data?
We must have a lawful basis for Processing your information; this will vary 			according to the circumstances of how and why we have your information but 		typical examples include:•	the activities are within our legitimate interests in advancing and maintaining the 		Roman Catholic religion, in providing information about the activities of Belmont 		Abbey , (e.g. where we use baptism data to follow up 	with families for first holy		communion) and to raise charitable funds;•	you have given consent (which can be withdrawn at any time by contacting 		us using the details below) for us to process your information (e.g. to send 		you marketing or fundraising communications by email or SMS);•	we are carrying out necessary steps in relation to a contract to which you are 		party or prior to you entering into a contract (e.g. where you enter into a booking with
Hedley Lodge, or
register for one of our retreats or events);•	the Processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation (e.g. 			where we pass on information to a local authority for safeguarding or other 		reasons);•	the Processing is necessary for carrying out a task in the public interest (e.g. 		updating and maintaining the register of marriages); or•	to protect your vital interests (e.g. if you were unfortunate enough to fall ill or 		suffer an injury on our premises, then we may pass on information to the 			NHS for treatment purposes and to family members).•	If we Process any Special Categories of Personal Data we must have a further 		lawful basis for the processing. This may include:•	where you have given us your explicit consent to do so (e.g. to cater for your 		medical or dietary needs at an event);•	where the Processing is necessary to protect your vital interests or someone 		else’s vital interests (e.g. passing on information to the Police);•	where the Processing is carried out in the course of our legitimate interests 		as a Roman Catholic Charity working with and supporting our current and 			former communities and parishioners and the information is not shared 			outside the Community other than with your consent (e.g. carrying 				out Community and parish censuses);•	you have made the information public;•	where the Processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or 			defence of legal claims;•	where the Processing is necessary for carrying out Belmont Abbey’s 			employment and social security obligations; or•	the processing being necessary for reasons of substantial public interest 			(e.g. where steps are taken to prevent fraud or other dishonest activity);			provided that the legal basis is proportionate to the aim pursued and 			provides for suitable and specific measures to safeguard your rights, or as 		part of our legitimate interests as a Roman Catholic charitable 				institution.•	If we Process any Personal Data comprising criminal convictions or offences we 		must also have a further lawful basis for the processing. This may include:		•	where we exercise obligations or rights which are imposed or 				conferred by law on us or you in connection with employment, social security or 		social protection and the Abbey has an appropriate policy document in place (e.g. 	to undertake appropriate checks on individuals prior to taking up a role);		•	where it is necessary for the prevention or detection of an unlawful act (e.g. passing 	on information to the Police or other investigatory body);•	where Belmont Abbey is complying with or assisting others to comply with 			regulatory requirements relating to unlawful acts or dishonesty (e.g. passing on 		information to the Police or other investigatory body);•	where it is carried out in the course of safeguarding children or other individuals at 	risk e.g. making a safeguarding disclosure;•	where an individual has given their consent to the processing;•	where Belmont Abbey is establishing, exercising or defending legal claims (e.g. 			providing information to our insurers or lawyers in connection with legal 			proceedings);•	where it is necessary to protect the vital interests of an individual (e.g. 			passing on information to the Police); or•	where it is carried out in the course of Belmont Abbey’s legitimate activities as a 		not-for-profit body with religious aims (e.g. carrying out pastoral activities).
Who will we share your information with?
We will only use your Personal Data within Belmont Abbey for the purposes for 		which it was obtained, unless you have explicitly agreed that we may share 		your Personal Data with another organisation or unless we are otherwise 			permitted or required to under the Data Protection Rules or order of a Court or 		other competent regulatory body or as set out in this Notice.•	Where relevant (e.g. parish information) we may share your information with other members of the Catholic Church seeking 	relief 	and any ecclesiastical body enjoying canonical jurisdiction or powers of 		governance as detailed in the Code of Canon law or the Apostolic 				Constitution Pastor Bonus.•	We may share your information with government bodies for tax purposes or law 		enforcement agencies for the prevention and detection of crime.•	Sometimes the Belmont Abbey contracts with third parties whom we ask to Process 	Personal Data on our behalf (e.g. IT consultants, distributors of parish newsletters 	and directories). We require these third parties to comply strictly with our 			instructions and with the GDPR.•	We also may be required to share your Personal Data so that Belmont Abbey can 	benefit from Gift Aid nominations you have made e.g. with HMRC.•	We have in place administrative, technical and physical measures designed to 		guard against and minimise the risk of loss, misuse or unauthorised processing or 	disclosure of the Personal Data that we hold.•	In the course of Processing your Personal Data, or disclosing it to the recipients 		referred to above, we may transfer it to countries which are outside the European 	Economic Area (EEA), some of which may not have laws which provide the same 	level of protection to your Personal Data as laws inside the EEA. In such cases we 	will take steps to ensure that the transfers comply with the GDPR and that your 		Personal Data is appropriately protected. We do so by taking the following 		measures:•	putting in place a contract with the recipient that means they must protect the 		personal information to the same standards as is required in the EEA;•	transferring it to a non-EEA country with privacy laws that give the same protection 	as the EEA;•	transferring it to organisations that are part of Privacy Shield (or any successor or 	replacement scheme). This is a framework that sets privacy standards for data sent 	between the US and EU countries to ensure that those standards are similar to 		what are used within the EEA;•	transferring it to organisations or countries that have other approved certification 		schemes or codes in place; or•	relying on another appropriate grounds under applicable data protection laws.
How long will we keep your information for?
Your information will be kept in accordance with our Retention & Disposal of 		Records Policy, copies of which are available from our Data Processing Officer:
In 			any event, we will endeavour to only keep Personal Data for as long as is 			necessary and to delete it when it is no longer necessary.•	Your rights•	You have rights in respect of the Personal Data you provide to us. In 			particular:•	the right to request a copy of some or all of the Personal Data that we hold 		about 	you (including, in some cases, in a commonly used, machine 			readable, format so that it can be transferred to other Data Controllers) . We 		do not make a charge for this service;•	if we Process your Personal Data on the basis that we have your consent, 			the right to withdraw that consent;•	the right to ask that any inaccuracies in your Personal Data are corrected;•	the right to have us restrict the Processing of all or part of your Personal 			Data;•	the right to ask that we delete your Personal Data where there is no 			compelling reason for us to continue to Process it;•	the right to object to us Processing your Personal Data for direct marketing 		purposes e.g. in relation to fundraising; and•	the right not to be subject to legal or other significant decisions being taken 		about you on the basis of an automated process (i.e. without human 			intervention).•	Please note that the above rights may be limited in some situations – for 			example, where we can demonstrate that we have a legal requirement to 			Process your Personal Data. Also, we may need you to provide us with proof 		of identity for verification and data security purposes before you can 			exercise your rights.•	Rights may only be exercised by the individual whose information is being 			held by the Belmont Abbey General Trust or with that individual’s express permission. Children 			from around 12 years upwards are entitled to make their own requests 			(where the Trust is of the reasonable view that they have an appropriate 		understanding of the request they are making) and parents / guardian / 			family members do not have an automatic right to see information about their 		child or prevent their child from making a request to us for information.
Changes to this Notice
We may make changes to this Notice from time to time as our organisational 		practices and/or applicable laws change. We will not make any use of your 		personal information that is inconsistent with the original purpose(s) for which it was collected or obtained (if we intend to do so, we will notify you in 			advance wherever possible) or otherwise than is permitted by data protection laws.
Contact Information
If you have any questions, require further information about how we protect 		your Personal Data, if you wish to exercise any of the above rights or if you 		would like to provide feedback or make a complaint about the use of your 			information, please contact us at:
Belmont Abbey, Ruckhall Lane, Hereford, 		HR2 9RZWe hope that we can satisfy any queries you may have about the way in 			which we Process your Personal Data. However, if you have unresolved 			concerns you also have the right to complain to the Information 				Commissioner (‘ICO’) (ico.org.uk).
Cookies
Cookies, also known as browsers or tracking cookies, are small text files that 		are added to your computer when you visit a website. They help websites to 		perform certain functions e.g. to know who you are if you log into a restricted 		part of a website, for shopping carts, and for tracking purposes.•	Belmont Abbey uses various cookies within our website. Full details of
the type of cookies used and access/control of these cookies 				can be located within our cookie policy page: the following 					cookies:•	Manage Cookies•	If you would like to opt-in or opt-out of using cookies then you should 			be able to do so using your browser. You can review your 					cookie settings at any time here.•	Please note that you cannot opt-out of the deployment of cookies that 			are necessary for delivery of our website or services to visitors these 			type of cookies will be outlined within our cookie policy page.
Glossary
“Data Controller” means a person, organisation or body that determines the purposes for which, and the manner in which, any Personal Data is processed. A Data Controller is responsible for complying with the data protection laws including the GDPR and establishing practices and policies in line with them.“Data Processor” means any person, organisation or body that Processes personal data on behalf of and on the instruction of the Belmont Abbey General Trust. Data Processors have a duty to protect the information they process by following data protection laws.“Data Subject” means a living individual about whom the Trust processes Personal Data and who can be identified from the Personal Data. A Data Subject need not be a UK national or resident. All Data Subjects have legal rights in relation to their Personal Data and the information that the Trust holds about them.“Personal Data” means any information relating to a living individual who can be identified from that information or in conjunction with other information which is in, or is likely to come into, the Trust's possession. Personal Data can be factual (such as a name, address or date of birth) or it can be an opinion (e.g. a performance appraisal). It can even include a simple email address. A mere mention of someone’s name in a document does not necessarily constitute Personal Data, but personal details such as someone’s contact details or salary (if it enabled an individual to be identified) would fall within the definition.“Processing” means any activity that involves use of Personal Data. It includes obtaining, recording or holding the information or carrying out any operation or set of operations on it, including organising, amending, retrieving, using, disclosing, erasing or destroying it. Processing also includes transferring or disclosing Personal Data to third parties.“Special Categories of Personal Data” (previously called sensitive personal data) means information about a person’s racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or similar beliefs, trade union membership, physical or mental health or condition or sexuality. It also includes genetic and biometric data. Special Categories of Personal Data can only be processed under strict conditions and such processing will usually, although not always, require the explicit consent of the Data Subject.
Home
Community
Abbot Paul
A Life in Community
Peru Monastery
Deceased Monks
History and Heritage
Prayer, Work and Study
Links Benedictine Monks in PeruEnglish Benedictine
CongregationOSB WebsiteHedley Lodge Guest House Terms and ConditionsPrivacy PolicySafeguarding
SAFEGUARDING
Our Monastery Belmont AbbeyRuckhall LaneHerefordHR2 9RZ Phone: 01432 374710E-mail: Enquirieswww.belmontabbey.org.uk
HOW TO FIND US
Get in touch: The Abbot Parish PriestThe PriorThe Retreats SecretaryThe Oblates MasterHedley LodgeAdditional ContactsContact the Web Master
Copyright 2018 © Belmont Abbey.  All rights reserved | “Belmont Abbey General CIO (registered charity number 1190035). Principal office: Belmont Abbey, Ruckall lane, Hereford HR2 9RZ.”Website developed by:
Every Day Christian Marketing Ltd
Share by:
